# KATHERINE JONES

Sandy Springs, GA 30328
Phone: 470-216-8864 Email: kejone1414@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/katherineetjones/ | Github: https://github.com/katjones23 | Portfolio: https://thedevkat.com/

#### SUMMARY

Adaptable and analytical Sharepoint Developer with a background in cloud-based platform administration and over 6 years of professional experience. Earned a Full-Stack Web Development certificate from Georgia Tech with skills in MERN. Proven ability to learn technical skills quickly while communicating it in an easy to understand language. Excellent critical thinking and analysis for problem solving and delivering solutions, taking ambiguous ideas to completed projects.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Languages:** JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Node.js, SQL, Express, Handelbars.js **Applications:** Visual Studio Code, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, GitHub, npm

#### OTHER SKILLS

SharePoint administration, Agile methodologies, project life-cycles, vendor and client relationship management, presentation skills, product knowledge

#### RECENT PROJECTS

**Project Name:** Build-A-Base

**Description:** An application for viewing and managing information from user-supplied

spreadsheets.

**Build information:** Collaboratively built full-stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node)

application.

https://github.com/AndreaGT91/spreadsheet-manager

https://spreadsheet-manager.herokuapp.com/

**Project Name:** Google Books Search

**Description:** An application connected to Google Books that allows users to search books, view them on Google Books, save them to the app, and delete them from the saved list.

Build information: Full-stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) application with Google Books

API.

https://github.com/katjones23/GoogleBooksSearch https://kj-google-books-search.herokuapp.com/

**Project Name:** User Directory

**Description:** An employee directory that allows for filtering based on department or employee

name. Columns can also be sorted.

**Build information:** Front-end web application built using React.

https://github.com/katjones23/UserDirectory | https://kj-user-directory.herokuapp.com/

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Technical Specialist** 2017 – 2021 **MarketSource** Alpharetta, GA

In addition to the responsibilities assumed under Systems Administrator:

- Developed, maintained, and improved SharePoint sites and Nintex forms and workflows to expedite processes touching multiple teams such as manual payouts and adding new job templates.
- Rapidly stood up a solution for 8 hotlines, SMS lines, and emails for a 12-member team to adapt their roles in response to COVID-19.
- Served as the technical lead in an implementation of a new contact center solution used across multiple teams and departments that provided a more streamlined service for 300+ users.
- Updating databases in Microsoft SQL Server on a daily basis.
- Administration and optimization of proprietary app REPFirst, used by field employees for scheduling, call reports, and communication.
- Continuous improvement and support of the company's use of software platforms, often as the single Subject Matter Expert.
- Collaborated with coworkers and other departments to enhance and optimize usage of current technologies.

# Systems Administrator MarketSource

2016 – 2017

Alpharetta, GA

- Supported user requests and troubleshoot reported issues through the ticketing system.
- Developed solutions for internal teams wanting to begin use of or increase use of the contact center solution.
- Created reporting based off the raw data provided by the platform and assisted the Analytics team in enhancing the reporting.

# Recruiting Specialist MarketSource

2014 - 2016

Alpharetta, GA

- Reviewed resumes for appropriateness of experience and knowledge in relation to position requirements
- Partnered with district managers to regularly establish rapport, gauge morale, and source new candidates
- Organized all pertinent applicant and interview data in the Applicant Tracking System (ATS)

#### **EDUCATION**

Bootcamp Certificate: Georgia Tech, Peachtree Corners, GA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

**Bachelor's in Chinese Language and Literature:** University of North Georgia, Dahlonega, GA **GPA:** 3.76/4.0

Awards & Honors: magna cum laude, Phi Kappa Phi, Psi Chi, Honors Program Graduate